Let's look a bit closer into Cross-Entropy by switching to a different example.
我们通过讲解另一个例子 进一步了解交叉熵
Let's say we have three doors.
假如我们有三个门
And no this is not the Monty Hall problem.
注意这不是蒙特霍尔问题
We have the green door, the red door,
我们有绿色 红色
and the blue door, and behind each door we could have a gift or not have a gift.
和蓝色的门 每个门后面可能有礼物 也可能没有
And the probabilities of there being a gift behind each door is 0.8 for the first one,
这些门后面有礼物的概率分别是 第一个门是 0.8
0.7 for the second one,
第二个门是 0.7
0.1 for the third one.
第三个门是 0.1
So for example behind the green door
那么绿门后面
there is an 80 percent probability of there being a gift,
有礼物的概率是 80%
and a 20 percent probability of there not being a gift.
没有礼物的概率是 20%
So we can put the information in this table where
我们把这些信息放入表格
the probabilities of there being a gift are given in the top row,
其中有礼物的概率放在上面一行
and the probabilities of there not being a gift are given in the bottom row.
没有礼物的概率放在下面一行
So let's say we want to make a bet on the outcomes.
假设我们想赌一赌结果
So we want to try to figure out what is the most likely scenario here.
想要计算这里最可能出现的场景
And for that we'll assume they're independent events.
为此我们假设它们是独立事件
In this case, the most likely scenario is just
在这个例子中 最可能出现的场景是
obtained by picking the largest probability in each column.
通过挑选每一列中的最大概率来获得
So for the first door is more likely to have a gift than not have a gift.
所以第一个门有礼物的可能性比没有礼物的可能性更大
So we'll say there's a gift behind the first door.
所以我们说第一个门后面有礼物
For the second door, it's also more likely that there's a gift.
对于第二个门 也是很有可能有礼物
So we'll say there's a gift behind the second door.
所以我们说第二个门后面有礼物
And for the third door it's much more likely that there's no gift,
对于第三个门 很有可能没有礼物
so we'll say there's no gift behind the third door.
所以我们说第三个门后面没有礼物
And as the events are independent,
因为这些事件是独立的
the probability for this whole arrangement is
整件事的概率是
the product of the three probabilities which is 0.8,
三个概率的乘积 即 0.8
times 0.7, times 0.9,
乘以 0.7 乘以 0.9
which ends up being 0.504,
最后得到 0.504
which is roughly 50 percent.
约为 50%
So let's look at all the possible scenarios in the table.
我们来观察表格中所有可能的场景
Here's a table with all the possible scenarios for each door
这个表格是每个门的所有场景
and there are eight scenarios since each door gives us two possibilities each,
由于每个门有两个结果 共有三个门
and there are three doors.
所以有八个场景
So we do as before to obtain the probability of
与之前求每个情况的概率相同 我们
each arrangement by multiplying the three independent probabilities to get these numbers.
通过三个独立概率相乘 得到这些数字
You can check that these numbers add to one.
你可以发现这些数字加起来等于 1
And from last video we learned that the negative
从上个视频中 我们了解到交叉熵中
of the logarithm of the probabilities across entropy.
负对数的概率
So let's go ahead and calculate the cross-entropy.
那么我们继续进行 计算交叉熵
And notice that the events with high probability have
注意高概率的事件
low cross-entropy and the events with low probability have high cross-entropy.
交叉熵低 而低概率的事件交叉熵高
For example, the second row which has probability of
例如第二行的概率是 0.504
0.504 gives a small cross-entropy of 0.69,
得到较小的交叉熵 0.69
and the second to last row which is very very unlikely has a probability of
倒数第二行概率仅为 0.006
0.006 gives a cross entropy a 5.12.
交叉熵是 5.12
So let's actually calculate a formula for the cross-entropy.
那么我们实际上可以计算交叉熵的公式
Here we have our three doors,
这里是我们的三个门
and our sample scenario said that there is a gift behind the first and second doors,
样本场景说明第一个门和第二个门后面有礼物
and no gift behind the third door.
第三个门后面没有礼物
Recall that the probabilities of these events happening
回想这些事件发生的概率
are 0.8 for a gift behind the first door,
第一个门后面有礼物的概率是 0.8
0.7 for a gift behind the second door,
第二个门后面有礼物的概率是 0.7
and 0.9 for no gift behind the third door.
第三个门后面没有礼物的概率是 0.9
So when we calculate the cross-entropy,
那么我们计算交叉熵后
we get the negative of the logarithm of the product,
我们负对数的乘积
which is a sum of the negatives of the logarithms of the factors,
即这些因子负对数的总和
which is negative logarithm of 0.8 minus logarithm of 0.7 minus logarithm 0.9.
即 0.8 的负对数乘以 0.7 的负对数乘以 0.9 的负对数
And in order to drive the formula we'll have some variables.
为了推导出公式 我们要有一些变量
So let's call P1 the probability that there's a gift behind the first door,
所以我们使用 P1 表示第一个门后面有礼物的概率
P2 the probability there's a gift behind the second door,
P2 表示第二个门后面有礼物的概率
and P3 the probability there's a gift behind the third door.
P3 表示第三个门后面有礼物的概率
So this 0.8 here is P1,
所以 0.8 是 P1
this 0.7 here is P2,
0.7 是 P2
and this 0.9 here is one minus P3.
0.9 是 1-P3
So it's a probability of there not being
那么没有礼物的概率等于
a gift is one minus the probability of there being a gift.
1 减去有礼物的概率
Let's have another variable called Yi,
我们使用另一个变量 叫做 Yi
which will be one of there's a present behind the ith door,
即如果第 i 个门后面有礼物 Yi 为 1
and zero there's no present.
如果没有礼物 Yi 为 0
So Yi is technically a number of presents behind the ith door.
所以从技术上讲 Yi 表示第 i 个门后面有一些礼物
In this case Y1 equals one,
那么在这个例子中 Y1 等于 1
Y2 equals one, and Y3 equals zero.
Y2 等于 1 Y3 等于 0
So we can put all this together and derive a formula
所以我们可以把这些加起来 推导出
for the cross-entropy and it's this sum.
交叉熵的公式 也就是这个总和
Now let's look at the formula inside the summation.
我们来观察一下这个总和内部的公式
Noted that if there is a present behind the ith door,
注意如果第 i 个门后面有礼物
then Yi equals one.
那么 Yi 等于 1
So the first term is logarithm of the Pi.
所以第一项是 ln(Pi)
And the second term is zero.
第二项是 0
Likewise, if there is no present behind the ith door,
类似地 如果第 i 个门后面没有礼物
then Yi is zero.
那么 Yi 等于 0
So this first term is zero.
那么第一项是 0
And this term is precisely logarithm of one minus Pi.
这一项是 ln(1-Pi)
Therefore, this formula really encompasses the sums of the
因此这个公式包含了
negative of logarithms which is precisely the cross-entropy.
负对数的总和 准确说是交叉熵的总和
So the cross-entropy really tells us when two vectors are similar or different.
所以交叉熵实际上说明了两个向量相似或不同时
For example, if you calculate the cross entropy of the pair one one zero,
例如 如果你计算一对 (1,1,0)
and 0.8, 0.7, 0.1, we get 0.69.
和 (0.8,0.7,0.1) 的交叉熵 我们得到 0.69
And that is low because one one zero is a similar vector to 0.8, 0.7, 0.1.
这个数字很低 是因为(1,1,0) 类似于 (0.8,0.7,0.1)
Which means that the arrangement of gifts given by the first set of
根据第二组数字的概率可以看出
numbers is likely to happen based
第一组数字相关的礼物顺序
on the probabilities given by the second set of numbers.
很有可能发生
But on the other hand if we calculate the cross-entropy of the pairs zero zero one,
不过另一方面 如果我们计算 (0,0,1) 和
and 0.8, 0.7, 0.1,
(0.8,0.7,0.1) 的交叉熵
that is 5.12 which is very high.
得到 5.12 这个结果很高
This is because the arrangement of gifts being given by the first set of numbers is
根据第二组数字的概率可以看出
very unlikely to happen from the probabilities given by the second set of numbers.
第一组数字相关的礼物顺序发生可能性更小